ANDRÉ V. G. S. GONÇALVES

Address: 3 Glasmeen Road - Dublin, Ireland \diamond Available to reallocate Phone: $+353~83~317~9400 \diamond$ Email: gsgandr3@gmail.com

SHORT BIO

I am a Telecommunications/Computer Engineer (BS/MS/PhD-in progress) with professional experience in Technical Support Engineering (tiers 1-3) and Computer Networks Management. Over the years, I have developed strong proficiency in Python, Linux (mostly Debian/Ubuntu), Bash scripting, Computer/Wireless Networks, and lately endeavoured in Machine Learning and Data Science. Among some relevant soft-skills, I list fast learner, team worker, and a good communicator.

TECHNICAL FEATURED SKILLS

- Python, Bash scripting, C/C++, Matlab/Octave.
- Machine and Reinforcement Learning.
- Linux Debian/Ubuntu, Git.
- Computer/Wireless Networks, and Software Defined Radio (Gnu Radio).

EXPERIENCE

CONNECT Centre - Dublin, Ireland

Mar 2019 - Present

PhD researcher

A team member of the project SATORI: Smart Networking in the Era of AI, http://satori-project.net.

Winet Research Lab. - Belo Horizonte, Brazil

Feb 2017 - Jan 2019

Master's researcher

Member of the Winet research group. Main research areas: applications of machine learning to wireless networks, self-organizing and cognitive networks. **Technical skills:** Python, C++, Machine/Reinforcement Learning, Gnu Radio. **Soft skills:** Technical and academic writing.

Kiffer TI - Belo Horizonte, Brazil

Aug 2017 - Nov 2018

Technical support analyst

On-site and on-demand IT technical support to Wabtec Corporation – Belo Horizonte, Brazil. **Technical skills:** Network troubleshooting and infrastructure, application support (Windows, TOTVS). **Soft skills:** On-site customer support environment experience.

Bwtech/NetChart – Belo Horizonte, Brazil Coordinator, Tier-3 support Engineer, Tier-2 support Intern, Tier-1 support Nov 2015 – May 2017Sep 2016 – Mar 2017Nov 2015 – Aug 2016

As a member of the support engineering team, my main daily activities consisted of: collecting and processing data from mobile networks (Operations Support Systems, OSS); assisting NetChart users; troubleshooting lack of data and OSS-related problems; and lastly, coordinating the activities of the support engineering team. **Technical skills:** Linux, Bash scripting, MySQL, .NET. **Soft skills:** Teamwork, Customer support environment experience.

Somers Entertainment – Adelaide, Australia

Aug 2014 - Nov 2014

Electronics Technician

Part-time job as an electronics technician, repairing sound and lighting equipment. **Technical skills:** Soldering, Electronics. **Soft skills:** English communication.

EDUCATION

Trinity College Dublin - Dublin, Ireland

Mar 2019 - Present

PhD student in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Supervisor: Luiz A. DaSilva

The Federal University of Minas Gerais – Belo Horizonte, Brazil

Feb 2017 - Jan 2019

Master's degree in Computer Science

Master's thesis: Troca automática de protocolos MAC empregando aprendizado por reforço (i.e., Automatic MAC protocol selection in wireless networks based on reinforcement learning). **GPA:** 9.3/10.

The University of Adelaide - Adelaide, Australia

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

Exchange program in Engineering

GPA: 7.7/10.

The Federal University of São João del-Rei – Ouro Branco, Brazil

Feb 2011 - Dec 2016

Bachelor's degree in Telecommunications Engineering

GPA: 8.7/10.

FURTHER COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

- CONNECT Centre Summer School. Machine Learning for Communication Systems and Networks.

 Organised by Trinity College Dublin.

 Sep 2-4 2019
- IEEE Summer School of Information Engineering (SSIE). AI and Machine Learning for ICT Applications. Organised by the University of Padova.

 Jul 8-12 2019
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization. Coursera. License 6Y8ZCRAD8QL2.
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning. Coursera. License FEV6C7P77SWF.
- Machine Learning. Coursera. License 4MGHZXQTNYBG.
- Introduction to Data Science in Python. Coursera. License 7QQPC83QL6W9.

AWARDS

- Master's degree scholarship. Funding granted by CAPES. Host university: The Federal University of Minas Gerais. Feb 2017 Jan 2019
- International student scholarship from the Brazilian educational program Science Without Borders. Funding granted by CNPq. Host university: The University of Adelaide.

 Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: native; English: proficient; Spanish: elementary.